Mohammad Ali (12/13/2003)

11594 218th Street, Cambria Heights NY 11411

(929) 413-8144 m.ali199753@gmail.com

OBJECTIVE

I intend to go through several experiences that will help enhance my intended future in computer science. I am always open to new things and ideas and love to learn new concepts that will help my future. I would like to involve myself in different software and methods, creating programs and applications, and much more!

EDUCATION

Queens College, NY 11367

BS in Computer Science

Starting August 2022 Expected May 2024

Achieved May 2022

Cumulative GPA: 3.861/4.0

Queensborough Community College, NY 11364

A.A.S in Internet and Information Technology

Relevant Coursework:

- Web Technology (Dreamweaver; HTML & CSS)
- Creating Smartphone Apps (Atom; HTML & CSS)
- Web Client Programming (Dreamweaver; JavaScript)
- Java Programming (Android Studio; Java)
- Programming and Applications (Thonny; Python)
- Linux Operating System (Linux)
- Advanced Web Multimedia Programming (Exposure to AWS Foundations, Angular, & Ruby)
- Operating System and Deployment (Windows 10)
- Networking (CISCO Packet Tracer, OSI Model, Starting and Configuring Networks)
- Database Technology (Exposure to AWS Architecture, Ruby, Rails, C.R.U.D)
- Computer Network Security (Security Design and Vulnerabilities)
- Robotics (Robotic Construction, Programming with C, ROBOTC, KISS IDE)

Business Technology Early College High School, NY 11427

High School Diploma

Achieved June 2021 Cumulative GPA: 4.0/4.0

Relevant Coursework:

- Technology Application (Tech privacy and security)
- AP Computer Science Principles

SKILLS

- Excellent interpersonal and communication skills
- Proficiency using Windows, Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint
- Acknowledged in Linux, Windows 10 and its role in the technology environment
- Acknowledged in creating basic websites and publishing them to the internet
- Acknowledged in the basics of computer coding languages such as C, Ruby, SQL, Python, JavaScript, Java, HTML, and CSS
- Acknowledged in basic networking fundamentals to design, build, and maintain networks

- Manage time and work in a proper fashion to execute the overall task(s)
- Exposure to AWS Foundations and Architecture and AWS Cloud Practitioner Certified
- Proficiency in Robot Fundamentals and coding to manipulate robots

PROJECTS

Children's Smartphone App

January 2021

- Designed and coded an app using HTML and CSS that contained a child friendly user-interface and allowed for child interaction.
- App was created through elements such as slideshows, animations, navigations, sounds, buttons, containers, and proper formatting.

Community Website

May 2020

- Designed and coded a website using HTML and CSS that would highlight a community in New York and give information about the community.
- The website was created through basic elements such as different pages, navigations, data forms, images, containers, headers, footers, and CSS formatting.

Exercise Android App

May 2021

- Designed and coded an android app using Java that would allow the user to have a guide on different muscle workouts.
- App was created through basic Java elements and contained buttons, links, embed video, and images.

Ruby on Rails Blog App and HR Resume Database App

May 2022

- Created a Rails application using basic principles of MVC and RESTful design through the use of a well-written guide.
- App was created using Ruby on Rails in AWS Cloud9 cloud-based IDE.
- It consisted of a connection to a database, general layout of a Rails application, MVC, and RESTful design using CRUD.
- Storage and update of application was done through GitHub.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Staples (Printing and Marketing), Bayside, NY, since January 2022

- Take customers' orders for printing and copying
- Print orders for business cards, posters, photos, etc.
- Responsible for delivering customer service according to need
- Collaborated with other team members to solve issues and problems
- Use selling skills to upsell and present solutions to customers

Staples (Merchandise), Bayside, NY, July 2021 – January 2022

- Responsible for helping customers according to their needs
- Able to multitask on cashier and merchandising department
- Lifted/Moved up to 50 pounds of materials/items
- Able to manage returns and issues faced by customer

Dunkin Donuts, Rockville Centre, NY, August 2020 to July 2021

- Responsible for serving quality products to customers with passion
- Work as part of a team to accommodate tasks and customer needs
- Answer customer's questions and help solve issues

Tutoring, Queens, NY, October 2018 to March 2020

• Assisting a seventh grader in her Math, English, Science, and Social Studies homework and accommodated with other tasks